Evan Hosni

Issaquah WA 98027 evanhosni.com -

- 360-704-0795 - linkedin.com/in/evanhosni

evankhaledhosni@gmail.comgithub.com/evanhosni

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a knack for UI/UX. Effective at combining creativity and problem solving to develop user-friendly applications. Always expanding knowledge by keeping abreast of the evolving trends, techniques, and technologies. Earned a bachelor's degree and bootcamp certificate and built professional experience in multiple industries.

SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript/jQuery/JSX, HTML, CSS, C#, Ruby (RGSS1)

Technologies: Node.js, Express.js, React.js, MySQL/Sequelize, MongoDB/Mongoose, JSON/API Integration,

WebGL, WebSockets/SocketIO, Git, GitHub, GitLab, Heroku

Applications: Webflow, Insomnia, MongoDB Compass, Adobe Creative Suite, Cubase, Pro Tools, Albeton,

Unity, Unreal Engine, Wwise (certified), FMOD, Blender

PROJECTS

[dotcomma] - dotcomma.io - gitlab.com/evanhosni/dotcomma

An browser-based MMO video game featuring all original music, 3D design, and animation, as well as an infinite, procedurally-generated terrain. (Still in early development).

Responsibilities: This is a solo project. I am developing the game in Unity, utilizing SocketIO for online multiplayer synchronization, and storing user data in a MySQL database.

Languages: C#, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Technologies: Unity, WebGL, FMOD, SocketIO, MySQL/Sequelize, Cubase, Blender, Adobe Photoshop

Pocket Rascal - evanhosni.github.io/pocket-rascal - github.com/evanhosni/pocket-rascal

A virtual pet to take care of, play games with, and customize.

Responsibilities: I was in charge of all frontend development, including UI/UX design, graphic design, and procedural animation. I also researched and implemented the Matter.js physics engine and developed plans for future monetization.

Languages: JavaScript/JSX, HTML, CSS

Technologies: React.js, Matter.js, Material UI, MySQL/Sequelize, Adobe Photoshop

Wacky-Wiki - evanhosni.github.io/wackywiki - github.com/evanhosni/wackywiki

A 'Mad Libs' style party game using any Wikipedia article.

Responsibilities: I was in charge of all frontend development, including UI/UX design and animation. I also was responsible for the integration of both the MediaWiki and Web Speech APIs.

Languages: JavaScript/jQuery, HTML, CSS

Technologies: MediaWiki API, Web Speech API, Bootstrap, Local Storage

MetaMemeMarket - <u>meta-meme-market.herokuapp.com</u> - <u>github.com/evanhosni/meta-meme-market</u> *A stock market for memes.*

Responsibilities: I was in charge of UX design and integration of the Cloudinary image hosting service, as well as the signup, login, logout, and upload image functionalities.

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Technologies: Express.js, Handlebars, MySQL/Sequelize, Cloudinary

WORK EXPERIENCE

AlphaBEST Education - Winston-Salem NC

January 2022 - Present

Web Developer (Remote)

- Developing an employee-facing intranet to facilitate communication and efficiency
- Collaborating with graphic designers to bring their vision to life via clean, responsive UI and UX
- Utilizing Webflow framework and Memberstack API as well as custom backend script to automate account creation and deletion via data from Google Sheets database

Evan is a great listener and always adds an element of fun - Brian, Chief Technology Officer

Evan Hosni Audio – Issaquah WA

December 2020 - Present

Sound Designer, Music Composer, Foley Artist, Audio Producer – Since graduating from Berklee, I have worked on two large-scale projects as an independent contractor. My clients and the scope of the projects are listed below:

DMAC Studios / Ultimate Invasion – Palm Beach FL

- Achieved IMDb credit as Sound Designer and Composer for all 8 episodes of Amazon Prime Video series, Ultimate Invasion
- Collaborated with Director Greg LeSar on the creative direction of the show's audio and met timesensitive deadlines

Green Mouse Academy - Palm Beach FL

- Produced audio for 100+ children's educational videos to date
- Collaborated with a team of editors to complete projects on time and developed strategies to streamline workflow

Evan masters the art of storytelling through audio. He was born to do this – Greg LeSar, Director/Writer – Ultimate Invasion

Evan, you are a talented professional and an absolute pleasure to work with – Shane VanderKooi, CEO – Green Mouse Academy

Guitar Center – Tukwila WA, Redmond WA

July 2015 - March 2021

Repair Technician – 2015 - 2019

Area Specialist – 2019 - 2021

- Cultivated a dedicated customer following by focusing on the customer experience
- Recognized by D'Addario Musical Instruments as a top performer in 2017
- Developed promotional programs to engage repair techs in incremental selling activities

Evan is a god among repair techs and an overall cool guy - Owen, Customer

EDUCATION

University of Washington Coding Boot Camp – Certificate of Completion August 2021 – December 2021 300+ hour course on dynamic full stack coding curriculum

Awarded Best UI/UX for all three student projects as well as People's Choice for 'Wacky-Wiki'

Berklee College of Music – Bachelor of Professional Studies

June 2016 - December 2020

Interdisciplinary Music Studies - Focus in Sound Design (Dean's List - six consecutive guarters)

Evan, another awesome soundscape! Man, I love hearing what you put together...really excited about this – Will Robertson, Professor